<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mind on Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/mind/</link><description>Recent content in mind on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>meditation: looking for myself</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</guid><description>Figure 1: Can you see a shapeless person in the picture? is it me? Made by Sveta Osborne
the word meditation has become more and more common in the content that i see online. everyone wants a quieter mind so they can make better decisions, improve focus, or continue some spiritual journey to find oneself.
i started this note to question whether i should try to meditate or not because i feel the need to better handle my attention span.</description></item><item><title>sport psychology: mind to perform</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m starting to understand the idea of sport psychology, seems like a variety of techniques to help an athlete to handle mental challenges.
the main techniques i have read about and found useful are:
visualization visualize the outcome you want while you rehearse your performance in your head make sure you see the event as how you want it to unfold if image turns negative, stop the mental tape use all your senses from a first-person perspective visualize in detail self-talk goal setting reflection this idea of mental training is fascinating, specially when you are young and you think that you have all the pressure of the world on your shoulders.</description></item></channel></rss>