<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>raw-page on Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/raw-page/</link><description>Recent content in raw-page on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Wanderson Ferreira</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 08:30:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/raw-page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>codebases as communication</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/codebases_as_communication/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 08:30:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/codebases_as_communication/</guid><description>Computer Things Conventionally we communicate programming ideas with talks, papers, and blog posts. But we can also communicate ideas with entire codebases. If someone finds a security exploit, she&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes publish a proof of concept to prove the exploit isn&amp;rsquo;t just theoretical.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s say the exploit PoC comes with a ton of command-line flags: verbose mode, configuration options, output formats, the whole works. Now the writer is communicating something subtly different: not just that the exploit exists, but she wants you to experiment with it.</description></item><item><title>abstraction: not what you think it is</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/abstraction_not_what_you_think_it_is/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:36:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/abstraction_not_what_you_think_it_is/</guid><description>March 28, 2022
“Interfaces are abstractions”
&amp;mdash; Olaf Thielke, the &amp;ldquo;Code Coach&amp;rdquo;
“Interfaces are not abstractions”
Mark Seeman, author of Code that Fits in Your Head and Dependency Injection
“Abstraction in programming is the process of identifying common patterns that have systematic variations; an abstraction represents the common pattern and provides a means for specifying which variation to use”
&amp;mdash; [[https://www.dreamsongs.com/Files/PatternsOfSoftware.pdf][Richard
Gabrie]]l, author of “The Rise of Worse is Better” and _Patterns of Software_</description></item><item><title>five things you notice when you quit the news</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/five_things_you_notice_when_you_quit_the_news/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:33:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/five_things_you_notice_when_you_quit_the_news/</guid><description>//Email
34K Shares
{ comments closed }
I grew up believing that following the news makes you a better citizen. Eight years after having quit, that idea now seems ridiculous&amp;mdash;that consuming a particularly unimaginative information product on a daily basis somehow makes you thoughtful and informed in a way that benefits society.
But I still encounter people who balk at the possibility of a smart, engaged adult quitting the daily news.</description></item></channel></rss>