<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>advices on Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/advices/</link><description>Recent content in advices on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Wanderson Ferreira</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:47:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/advices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>how expert programmers think about errors</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/notes/how_expert_programmers_think_about_errors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:47:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/notes/how_expert_programmers_think_about_errors/</guid><description>Link of the talk.
pay attention to what is hidden attending to contrary evidence seek falsification write comments about what is not in the code: intentions and assumptions understanding by breaking re-assessing the landscape and deliberately expanding the search space sometimes a high performance team avoids using methodologies playing methods against each other building errors into the code to verify the test suite etc the interplay between developers is crucial experts use disciplined practices that are socially embedded and reinforced contrasting multiple perspectives fixes the problem and not worries about the blame</description></item><item><title>value and waste in software engineering</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/notes/value_and_waste_in_software_engineering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:44:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/notes/value_and_waste_in_software_engineering/</guid><description> what is waste?
bad code reviews building the wrong feature or product mismanaging the backlog rework unecessarily complex solutions extraneous cognitive load psychological distress knowledge loss waiting ineffective communication human values?
maintain honour + respect for users e.g. what user information is kept, how is it shared? facilitate different origins, languages, cultures, knowledge</description></item><item><title>fundamentals</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/notes/fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 21:01:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/notes/fundamentals/</guid><description>Bird must soar. Skunk must stink.
Cat must prowl. Man must think.
What sets man apart from beast is his engine of
thought. His mind. His
BRAIN
makes him unique
and gives his greatest pleasure.
But fundamental as is thought for human beings,
there is stuff more basic still that underlies and
DRIVES
not only man
but all great beasts,
And that is nature&amp;rsquo;s call to each of us&amp;hellip; to be special.</description></item><item><title>what to learn?</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/what_to_learn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 08:10:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/what_to_learn/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s common to see people advocate for learning skills that they have or using processes that they use. For example, Steve Yegge has a set of blog posts where he recommends reading compiler books and learning about compilers. His reasoning is basically that, if you understand compilers, you&amp;rsquo;ll see compiler problems everywhere and will recognize all of the cases where people are solving a compiler problem without using compiler knowledge. Instead of hacking together some half-baked solution that will never work, you can apply a bit of computer science knowledge to solve the problem in a better way with less effort.</description></item><item><title>what's enlightenment?</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/what_s_enlightenment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 08:10:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/what_s_enlightenment/</guid><description>Published at [Columbia Edu](http://www.columbia.edu/acis/ets/CCREAD/etscc/kant.html) Immanuel Kant Enlightenment is man&amp;rsquo;s emergence from his self-imposed nonage. Nonage is the inability to use one&amp;rsquo;s own understanding without another&amp;rsquo;s guidance. This nonage is self-imposed if its cause lies not in lack of understanding but in indecision and lack of courage to use one&amp;rsquo;s own mind without another&amp;rsquo;s guidance. Dare to know! (Sapere aude.) &amp;ldquo;Have the courage to use your own understanding,&amp;rdquo; is therefore the motto of the enlightenment.</description></item></channel></rss>