<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 21:30:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>meditation</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</guid><description>the word meditation has become more and more common. everyone wants a quieter mind so they can make better s and improve focus.
there are different kinds of meditations:
zen meditation tibetan meditation indian meditation why one should medidate and what is the significance of meditation?
purposes of why people are trying to it nowadays:
peace of mind better understanding of themselves we need to question things, it is good to have , to be skeptical up to a certain point.</description></item><item><title>focus: the ability to control our attention</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</guid><description>Figure 1: Acrylic painting describing a narrowing tunnel using shades of black, blue, and white. Seems to have a person by the end of it, but i am not sure.
focus can be defined as the ability to carefully pay attention to something such as a task or a person.
it requires a lot of concentration.
in the world of sport psycology, focus is a critical skill that must be mastered by all athletes that desire to exceed in their role.</description></item><item><title>sport psychology: put yourself together to perform</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m starting to understand the idea of sport psychology, seems like a variety of techniques to help an athlete to handle mental challenges.
this idea of is fascinating, specially when you are young and you think that you have all the pressure of the world on your shoulders.
nice that I know more about this now, who knows if anyone from my will ever need this kind of support.
for now, I am struggling with the process to become a , at least i have identified some of the main pain points that i am facing:</description></item><item><title>how do i blog</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</guid><description>This is a meta post in order to teach myself from the future how to do it!
I often spend a few weeks without the desire to write anything in my blog (I should fix that but let&amp;rsquo;s be real first), but at some moment I do want to type some letters down.. but they I freeze.. how do I do it?
These are the steps I used to write this blog post starting from complete scratch:</description></item><item><title>reference missing</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</guid><description>due to lazyness, incomplete work or privacy, the reference you are trying to follow does not exist yet.
contact me if this is important to you at this point: [wand at hey dot com]</description></item></channel></rss>