<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 11:28:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Semana 4: Ciclo Maratona de SP 2025</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 11:28:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-4/</guid><description>Quarta semana!</description></item><item><title>Semana 3: Ciclo Maratona de SP 2025</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:28:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-3/</guid><description>Terceira semana!</description></item><item><title>Semana 2: Ciclo Maratona de SP 2025</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 11:28:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-2/</guid><description>O ritmo começou a apertar um pouco. Longão em um pace bacana, não muito lento e nem rápido. Boa semana essa!</description></item><item><title>patience</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614220742-patience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614220742-patience/</guid><description>Figure 1: La Patience des Arbres.
Searching for patience in different contexts I found a good definition from psychology professor that believes that patience is situational form of emotion regulation, quote:
When we feel the emotion of impatience, patience is the name of the self-regulation tools we apply to cope with that feeling. Whether that&amp;rsquo;s self-talk, deep breaths, or preemption, those subtle or explicit self-control strategies in the face of uncertain, stressful waiting are acts of patience.</description></item><item><title>Semana 1: Ciclo Maratona de SP 2025</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:28:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/maratona-sp-2025-semana-1/</guid><description>Primeira semana! Voltando após as minhas primeiras 2 meia-maratonas. Não sei se foi uma boa idéia ter feito a prova na Estrada Velha de Santos.</description></item><item><title>yuná: primeira bike artesanal</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240911205432-yuna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240911205432-yuna/</guid><description>yuná significa &amp;ldquo;em prol da união&amp;rdquo;, e esse nome foi cuidadosamente escolhido para simbolizar harmonia e colaboração entre as pessoas. a bike tem seu quadro e garfo produzidos em aço hi ten pelo projeto hito enquanto a montagem fica de responsabilidade da las magrelas.
marcas nacionais o projeto da las magrelas utiliza alguns componentes de marcas nacionais como o pedivela da nottable metal works e o trabalho artesanal do projeto hito para a fabricação do quadro e garfo</description></item><item><title>meditation: looking for myself</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</guid><description>Figure 1: Can you see a shapeless person in the picture? is it me? Made by Sveta Osborne
the word meditation has become more and more common in the content that i see online. everyone wants a quieter mind so they can make better decisions, improve focus, or continue some spiritual journey to find oneself.
i started this note to question whether i should try to meditate or not because i feel the need to better handle my attention span.</description></item><item><title>focus: the ability to control our attention</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</guid><description>Figure 1: Most of my time my focus is blurred and difficult to manage. Is it normal? I can only tell for myself. Made by Sue5Ft1
focus can be defined as the ability to carefully pay attention to something such as a task or a person.
it requires a lot of concentration.
in the world of sport psycology, focus is a critical skill that must be mastered by all athletes that desire to exceed in their role.</description></item><item><title>sport psychology: mind to perform</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m starting to understand the idea of sport psychology, seems like a variety of techniques to help an athlete to handle mental challenges.
the main techniques i have read about and found useful are:
visualization visualize the outcome you want while you rehearse your performance in your head make sure you see the event as how you want it to unfold if image turns negative, stop the mental tape use all your senses from a first-person perspective visualize in detail self-talk goal setting reflection this idea of mental training is fascinating, specially when you are young and you think that you have all the pressure of the world on your shoulders.</description></item><item><title>how do i blog</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</guid><description>This is a meta post in order to teach myself from the future how to do it!
I often spend a few weeks without the desire to write anything in my blog (I should fix that but let&amp;rsquo;s be real first), but at some moment I do want to type some letters down.. but they I freeze.. how do I do it?
These are the steps I used to write this blog post starting from complete scratch:</description></item><item><title>reference missing</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/posts/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</guid><description>due to lazyness, incomplete work or privacy, the reference you are trying to follow does not exist yet.
contact me if this is important to you at this point: [wand at hey dot com]</description></item></channel></rss>