<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>readings on Bartuka</title>
    <link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/readings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in readings on Bartuka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/readings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary readings: April - December 2020</title>
      <link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/blog/summary-readings-rest-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/blog/summary-readings-rest-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://eli.thegreenplace.net/&#34;&gt;Eli Bendersky&lt;/a&gt; blog, and he
produces a very simple and not so detailed summary of all his book
readings from time to time. This is very useful because I like to read
and one of the most difficult tasks for me is searching &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to read
(you know, time is limited).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I decided to do the same. I also try to keep track of my
&lt;em&gt;to-read&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; books since 2016 at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/85018850-wanderson-ferreira&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;,
I hope to help someone else choosing the next book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-invisible-cities&#34;&gt;1. Invisible Cities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This said, it is pointless trying to decide whether Zenobia is to be
classified among happy cities or among the unhappy. It makes no
sense to divide cities into these two species, but rather into
another two: those that through the years and the changes continue
to give their form to desires, and those in which desires either
erase the city or are erased by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Marco Polo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Invisible-Cities-Italo-Calvino-ebook/dp/B00ALJH62U&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would read again? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very different book, it is about an Emperor with a vast realm, and
he personally does not know all the cities, thus he has explorers
to visit the cities and to describe them for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the descriptions from Marco Polo are very unusual, we are
invited to look at the real elements that constitute the city
metaphor e.g. people, culture, relationships, believes, tradition,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several cities shared similarities with so many “cities”
I lived inside São Paulo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-the-nonexisting-knight&#34;&gt;2. The Nonexisting Knight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What d&amp;rsquo;you expect to be sure of? [&amp;hellip;]. Insignia, ranks, titles
. . . All mere show. Those paladins&amp;rsquo; shields with armorial bearings
and mottoes are not made of iron; they&amp;rsquo;re just paper, you can put
your finger through them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Torrismund&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Nonexistent-Knight-Cloven-Viscount/dp/0156659751/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would read again? Sure!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book tells the history of Agilulf which is a pristine knight!
He is the perfect knight, everything is done correctly and
precisely, he knows all the rules and protocols and never fail any
assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of the tale is to confront the notion of identity. What we
find out by looking at Agilulf is very sad because we realize that
following rules, and optimizing around made up concepts and
protocols is very easy and you can perform all these tasks very
precisely without thinking too much about “why” questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a connection with another subject I read in the past called
&lt;strong&gt;”Bad Faith”&lt;/strong&gt; by the French philosopher Jean-Paul Sartre. Living
in “bad faith” is lying to yourself about your options, “things
must be this way”, “this is my destiny”, and so on. accordingly, to
Sartre, bad faith happens as an alternative to the scare notion of
Freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-the-tao-of-microservices&#34;&gt;3. The Tao of Microservices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But concepts are useless without practice. You can&amp;rsquo;t understand how
to build software in a new way, without building software in a new
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manning.com/books/the-tao-of-microservices&#34;&gt;Manning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would read again? As soon as I need to work on Microservice again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two years searching / reading about MS, this is probably one
of the best books/resources I found so far. The book is an
“experience report” from the author last 6 years building
microservices in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As everything in software, this is not the only way or the “right”
way, but has several discussions about trade-offs you will
eventually need to make if you go down this road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have several footnotes in the book pages that I wish I could
discuss further with the author, this is my feature request for
books in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-release-it&#34;&gt;4. Release It!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some software exists as art and some exists as entertainment. Most
of the software we write for companies exists to create economic
value. We should build our systems with transparency in terms of
revealing the way that the recent past, current state, and future
state connect to revenue and costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Release-Production-Ready-Software-Pragmatic-Programmers-ebook/dp/B00A32NXZO&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would read again? Not cover-to-cover, but as reference guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book presents several topics for running software in production
for real companies based on a series of Case Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find very useful to read about experience reports because there
are very wild situations that only happen in production after years
of development. This problem might be related to what Joe Armstrong
describes in &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lKXe3HUG2l4?t=879&#34;&gt;The Mess We&amp;rsquo;re
In&lt;/a&gt; when he talks about the
incredible number of possible states a computer can be at any given
time. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the reason you can&amp;rsquo;t fully reproduce the same
bug twice in many situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-masters-of-doom-how-two-guys-created-an-empire-and-transformed-pop-culture&#34;&gt;5. Masters of Doom: How Two Guys Created An Empire And Transformed Pop Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the information age, the barriers just aren&amp;rsquo;t there&amp;rdquo;, he
said. &amp;ldquo;The barriers are self-imposed. If you want to set off and go
develop some grand new thing, you don&amp;rsquo;t need millions of dollars of
capitalization. You need enough pizza and Diet Coke to stick in your
refrigerator, a cheap PC to work on, and the dedication to go
through with it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; John Carmack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Masters-Doom-Created-Transformed-Culture-ebook/dp/B000FBFNL0/ref=sr_1_1?crid=I7UC6N25UF84&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=masters+of+doom&amp;amp;qid=1608786622&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sprefix=masters+of+doom%2Cdigital-text%2C289&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate: 3/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would read again? No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of the book is very good, however I think I lost the
passion for books written in J.R.R Tolkien style. Lots of details
about the whole scene. I also understand that this style portrait
the exact situation of the Game industry back at that time and how
two guys could deliver a bunch of innovative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the book mentions other works being developed at
Universities and other places, the power of John Carmack and John
Romero was to be able to ship code! To make that thing useful in
some context and to never give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the game industry today has similar working conditions
to their employees but without the appropriate upside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-head-first-design-patterns&#34;&gt;6. Head First Design Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Pattern is a solution to a problem in a given context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com.br/Head-First-Design-Patterns-Freeman/dp/0596007124&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would read again? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in my waiting list since 2015. The book is indeed very
interesting and it has very nice ideas about how to approach the
design of your problem space to enable more flexibility, and less
friction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I use Functional Languages in my daily job, I
understand a lot of valuable concepts behind OOP that should be
used anyway e.g. composition, dependency inversion, program towards
interfaces to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even created a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wandersoncferreira/hfdp&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt; to
implement all the examples from the book in Clojure with a Java
accent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description> 
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary readings: March - April 2020</title>
      <link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/blog/summary-readings-march-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/blog/summary-readings-march-april/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://eli.thegreenplace.net/&#34;&gt;Eli Bendersky&lt;/a&gt; blog and he
produces a very simple and not so detailed summary of all his book
readings from time to time. This is very useful because I like to read
and one of the most difficult tasks for me is searching &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to read
(you know, time is limited).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I decided to do the same. I also try to keep track of my
&lt;em&gt;to-read&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt; books since 2016 at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/85018850-wanderson-ferreira&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;,
I hope to help someone else choosing the next book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-surely-youre-joking-mr-feynman---by-richard-p-feynman&#34;&gt;1. &lt;em&gt;Surely You&amp;rsquo;re Joking Mr. Feynman!&lt;/em&gt; - by Richard P. Feynman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should go to some other school. You should find out how the rest
of the world it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Professor Slate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/What-Care-Other-People-Think-ebook/dp/B004OA6KIS/ref=sr_1_2?crid=LILHFC7OIE0&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=surely+you+are+joking&amp;amp;qid=1587699386&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sprefix=surely+you+are%2Cdigital-text%2C285&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rated: 5/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read again? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I postponed this reading for a long time, but what a bad decision!.
This book is very nice! As a previous (geo)physicist student, I very
often you read and listened about the great work of some scientists
and Feynman was definitely one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study at Universidade de São Paulo and Feynman came to Brazil and
was there for a while (there is even a chapter about that!!) so he was
&lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; figure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book shows how &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; Feynman was! He had an incredible
curiosity and willpower to act upon his experiments. So many funny
histories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He described one of this presentation about his academic work and on
the audience was Einstein, Oppenheimer, Norris Russell, von Neumann,
and many others. Wow! I personally relate to that because in 2014 I
presented my findings in Houston to many great geophysicist that I had
only met before by reading their work on journals. The feeling is
great, rush of adrenaline when you start talking about the subject
that you have been investigating for 2 years in a row .. you &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt;
you are the expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have just one wish to you &amp;ndash; the good luck to be somewhere
where you are free to maintain the kind of integrity I have described,
and where you do not feel forced by a need to maintain your position
in the organization, or financial support, or so on, to lose your
integrity. May you have that freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-the-complete-problem-solver---by-john-r-hayes&#34;&gt;2. &lt;em&gt;The Complete Problem Solver&lt;/em&gt; - by John R. Hayes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can influence their own learning processes and have a great
deal to gain by doing so. By 1. choosing to distribute practice, 2.
select appropriate learning strategies, and 3. using evaluation of
progress to control study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Complete-Problem-Solver-John-Hayes-ebook/dp/B00C7TB1XM/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=the+complete+problem+solver&amp;amp;qid=1587699347&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rated: 3/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read again? No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More detail and technical explanation about the components involved
at &lt;em&gt;solving problems&lt;/em&gt; such as &lt;em&gt;memory&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;proper problem
representation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;creativity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;decision making&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is indeed interesting, but I think if you are into some of these
subjects you already know 80% of this book. However, if you are only
interested in starting, this is a very dense read. Therefore, I do not
find it worthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a nice study about creativity though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] These results &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; mean that there is no such thing as
genius. They &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; mean that just anyone with 10 to 25 years of
experience can write great music. They &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; mean that even a person
endowed with the genius of Mozart or Beethoven will need 10 years
or more of intense preparation to be creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-the-clean-coder---by-robert-c-martin-uncle-bob&#34;&gt;3. &lt;em&gt;The Clean Coder&lt;/em&gt; - by Robert C. Martin (Uncle Bob)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All professionals practice their art by engaging in skill-sharpening
exercises. Musicians rehearse scales, Football players run through
tires, &lt;em&gt;Doctors&lt;/em&gt; practice sutures and surgical techniques, &lt;em&gt;Lawyers&lt;/em&gt;
practice arguments. When performance matters, professionals
practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Clean-Coder-Conduct-Professional-Programmers-ebook/dp/B0050JLC9Y/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=the+clean+coder&amp;amp;qid=1587699322&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rated: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read again? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy and good to read, the message is harsh towards &lt;em&gt;programmer&amp;rsquo;s
profissionalism&lt;/em&gt; and very eye opener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with a history about a project where the business manager
was paired up with the technical leader and they were kicking in all
the obstacles to deliver all the features, working really intense
hours to deliver on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, at the release date the &lt;em&gt;legal department&lt;/em&gt; could not
finish a necessary contract to go live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical leader says to the business manager: &amp;ldquo;ok, let&amp;rsquo;s do our
thing again and go there and ask them to finish this two pages by the
end of the day!&amp;rdquo; and the answer caught the technical leader with great
surprise: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;we cannot do this, they are real professionals&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait a moment! Wait a moment&amp;hellip;!! What am I? Wait a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software development &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; processes, rituals and ways at we
can act and perform like professionals and most of the time we &lt;em&gt;should
not violate&lt;/em&gt; these &lt;em&gt;principles&lt;/em&gt; because of our work ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might negotiate with business people the correct estimates to
deliver everything, and we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; professionals, we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to deliver
the product, we are a member of this organization, we work on the
company&amp;rsquo;s side. There are no reasons for me to be lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is difficult. Because the developers itself does not take
themselves serious enough, how can the management do it so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Language of commitment: Say. Mean. Do.  &amp;ndash; Roy Osherove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-the-joy-of-clojure---by-michael-fogus&#34;&gt;4. &lt;em&gt;The Joy of Clojure&lt;/em&gt; - by Michael Fogus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you give someone Fortran, he has Fortran. If you give someone
Lisp, he has any language he pleases. &amp;ndash; Guy Steele&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Joy-Clojure-Michael-Fogus/dp/1617291412/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=joy+of+clojure&amp;amp;qid=1587699263&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rated: 5/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read again? Always reaching out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes is not clear to people when I say that I am studying
Clojure. The language itself has lots of interesting bits, but very
often the subjects that interest me most are the reasoning behind
how Clojure was design and how it is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fogus goes deep in each aspect of the language and provides several
valuable references to papers or books in order to improve our
understanding about the concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that Clojure was designed &amp;ldquo;by/to experienced programmers&amp;rdquo;
makes it very interesting to me. I haven&amp;rsquo;t participated in
communities with such a high quality discussions and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It requires a very unusual mind to undertake the analysis of the
obvious. &amp;ndash; Alfred North Whitehead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-meditations---by-marcus-aurelius&#34;&gt;5. &lt;em&gt;Meditations&lt;/em&gt; - by Marcus Aurelius&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first rule is to keep an untroubled spirit. The second is to
look things in the face and know them for what they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Meditations-AmazonClassics-Marcus-Aurelius-ebook/dp/B07QQRGH6R/ref=sr_1_2?crid=CQUKNCRBJHCO&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=meditations+by+marcus&amp;amp;qid=1587699224&amp;amp;s=digital-text&amp;amp;sprefix=medidations%2Cdigital-text%2C292&amp;amp;sr=1-2&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rated: 4/5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read again? Maybe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very easy read, Marcus Aurelius was an Roman Emperor and also a
Stoic Philosopher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this book right after reading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Zen-Mind-Beginners-Informal-Meditation-ebook/dp/B00I8USOM0/ref=pd_sbsd_14_1/136-4339934-2460642?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=B00I8USOM0&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=e82a0562-5bc2-496b-aeff-ddef62decae3&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=wzsZ2&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=TNaZz&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=2c2d0d3b-b3c5-4110-93fa-2c1270309ac1&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=ZG3N26GRJBCNETGJ5XTD&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=ZG3N26GRJBCNETGJ5XTD&#34;&gt;Zen
Mind&lt;/a&gt;,
which is a book about Zen Practice and Buddhism, and I was astonished
to notice so many similarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is basically a Twitter Account from 120d.C. Amazing to see how
he thinks and his priorities back them, also some chad of light about
society. You should definitely read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that everything has always been the same, and keeps recurring,
and it makes no difference whether you see the same things recur in
a hundred years or two hundred, or in an infinite period;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that the longest-lived and those who will die soonest lose the
same thing. The present is all that they can give up, since that is
all you have, and what you do not have you cannot lose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description> 
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
