<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bookmark on Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/bookmark/</link><description>Recent content in bookmark on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Wanderson Ferreira</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 08:31:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/bookmark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>todo entrypoint file</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/todo_entrypoint_file/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 08:31:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/todo_entrypoint_file/</guid><description>This is a set of raw pages that I want to take at look before turning them into actual bookmarks or posts
dreyfus model of skill acquisition M-x Research videos GeePawHill Tweet on the State of Hiring Programmers are we really engineers? dopamine, smartphones &amp;amp; you: a battle for your time research as understanding distributed systems lecture notes - Dr. Martin Kleppmann Tonsky thread on things learned from other programming languages Python WSGI Michael Sugrue Lectures on philosophy stanford cs 253 web security when did computer science theory get so hard?</description></item><item><title>codebases as communication</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/codebases_as_communication/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 08:30:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/bookmarks/codebases_as_communication/</guid><description>Computer Things Conventionally we communicate programming ideas with talks, papers, and blog posts. But we can also communicate ideas with entire codebases. If someone finds a security exploit, she&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes publish a proof of concept to prove the exploit isn&amp;rsquo;t just theoretical.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s say the exploit PoC comes with a ton of command-line flags: verbose mode, configuration options, output formats, the whole works. Now the writer is communicating something subtly different: not just that the exploit exists, but she wants you to experiment with it.</description></item></channel></rss>