<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>publish on Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/publish/</link><description>Recent content in publish on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/publish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>meditation: looking for myself</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</guid><description>Figure 1: Can you see a shapeless person in the picture? is it me? Made by Sveta Osborne
the word meditation has become more and more common on the content that i see online. everyone wants a quieter mind so they can make better decisions, improve focus, or continue some spiritual journey to find oneself.
i started this note to question whether i should try to meditate as well because i feel the need to better handle my attention span.</description></item><item><title>focus: the ability to control our attention</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</guid><description>Figure 1: Most of my time my focus is blurred and difficult to manage. Is it normal? I can only tell for myself.
focus can be defined as the ability to carefully pay attention to something such as a task or a person.
it requires a lot of concentration.
in the world of sport psycology, focus is a critical skill that must be mastered by all athletes that desire to exceed in their role.</description></item><item><title>sport psychology: put yourself together to perform</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m starting to understand the idea of sport psychology, seems like a variety of techniques to help an athlete to handle mental challenges.
this idea of mental training is fascinating, specially when you are young and you think that you have all the pressure of the world on your shoulders.
nice that I know more about this now, who knows if anyone from my family will ever need this kind of support.</description></item><item><title>how do i blog</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</guid><description>This is a meta post in order to teach myself from the future how to do it!
I often spend a few weeks without the desire to write anything in my blog (I should fix that but let&amp;rsquo;s be real first), but at some moment I do want to type some letters down.. but they I freeze.. how do I do it?
These are the steps I used to write this blog post starting from complete scratch:</description></item><item><title>reference missing</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</guid><description>due to lazyness, incomplete work or privacy, the reference you are trying to follow does not exist yet.
contact me if this is important to you at this point: [wand at hey dot com]</description></item></channel></rss>