<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>publish on Wanderson Ferreira</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/publish/</link><description>Recent content in publish on Wanderson Ferreira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/tags/publish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>yuná: minha primeira bike artesanal</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240911205432-yuna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/home/bartuka/code/roam/notes/20240911205432-yuna/</guid><description>yuná significa &amp;ldquo;em prol da união&amp;rdquo;, e esse nome foi cuidadosamente escolhido para simbolizar harmonia e colaboração entre as pessoas. a bike tem seu quadro e garfo produzidos em aço hi ten pelo projeto hito enquanto a montagem fica de responsabilidade da las magrelas.
marcas nacionais o projeto da las magrelas utiliza alguns componentes de marcas nacionais como o pedivela da nottable metal works e o trabalho artesanal do projeto hito para a fabricação do quadro e garfo</description></item><item><title>meditation: looking for myself</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240622060436-meditation/</guid><description>Figure 1: Can you see a shapeless person in the picture? is it me? Made by Sveta Osborne
the word meditation has become more and more common in the content that i see online. everyone wants a quieter mind so they can make better decisions, improve focus, or continue some spiritual journey to find oneself.
i started this note to question whether i should try to meditate or not because i feel the need to better handle my attention span.</description></item><item><title>focus: the ability to control our attention</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240615110814-focus/</guid><description>Figure 1: Most of my time my focus is blurred and difficult to manage. Is it normal? I can only tell for myself. Made by Sue5Ft1
focus can be defined as the ability to carefully pay attention to something such as a task or a person.
it requires a lot of concentration.
in the world of sport psycology, focus is a critical skill that must be mastered by all athletes that desire to exceed in their role.</description></item><item><title>sport psychology: put yourself together to perform</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240614214250-sport-psychologist/</guid><description>i&amp;rsquo;m starting to understand the idea of sport psychology, seems like a variety of techniques to help an athlete to handle mental challenges.
this idea of mental training is fascinating, specially when you are young and you think that you have all the pressure of the world on your shoulders.
nice that I know more about this now, who knows if anyone from my family will ever need this kind of support.</description></item><item><title>how do i blog</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915184711-how-do-i-blog/</guid><description>This is a meta post in order to teach myself from the future how to do it!
I often spend a few weeks without the desire to write anything in my blog (I should fix that but let&amp;rsquo;s be real first), but at some moment I do want to type some letters down.. but they I freeze.. how do I do it?
These are the steps I used to write this blog post starting from complete scratch:</description></item><item><title>reference missing</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915190218-reference-missing/</guid><description>due to lazyness, incomplete work or privacy, the reference you are trying to follow does not exist yet.
contact me if this is important to you at this point: [wand at hey dot com]</description></item><item><title>improve my notes content</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915151715-improve-my-notes-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20240915151715-improve-my-notes-content/</guid><description>Figure 1: Seems to be the mood I turn myself when I decide to write a note. Made by Jack B Yeats, Irish, 1871-1957.
i&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking if the way i am currently writting my notes could be significantly improved with little effort. my main object is to be able to continue to collect thought in a way that does not require much structure and formalism however i am also aware that many tools in the future could be used to parse and extract useful information from these notes.</description></item><item><title>primeira maratona</title><link>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20250102100219-primeira-maratona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wandersoncferreira.github.io/users/wferreir/code/roam/notes/20250102100219-primeira-maratona/</guid><description>Escolhi fazer a maratona de São Paulo como primeira maratona em 06 de Abril de 2025. E estou bem animado para conhecer a reação do meu corpo com esse volume de treinamento diferente. Também estou um pouco preocupado sobre a conciliação desse treino com os demais compromissos que eu possuo no meu dia-a-dia. Mas por enquanto estou conseguindo lidar com isso, as coisas vão ficar bem mais complicadas em Março de 2025.</description></item></channel></rss>